<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Jake Kaupp</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Jake Kaupp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#IVMOOC Week 1: All in the family</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-01-22-ivmooc-week-1-all-in-the-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-01-22-ivmooc-week-1-all-in-the-family/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve made it through the first week of #IVMOOC. Gold stars all around! I did learn some new things, new tricks and new tools from the lectures and I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for a good framework. Anything that can help me organize chaos in a logical, well though out manner appeals to the engineer in me. As an avid R and RStudio user, I love the SCI2 tool, and how it melds data wrangling aspects with the visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#IVMOOC Week 2: Wibbley-wobbly timey-wimey stuff</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-01-29-ivmooc-week-2-wibbley-wobbly-timey-wimey-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-01-29-ivmooc-week-2-wibbley-wobbly-timey-wimey-stuff/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m liking this course. The videos are easy to listen to and are in nice manageable chunks that I can watch them while making dinner, or on a quick break from work. I especially liked the discussion of the burst-detection model this week, although I would have enjoyed a more in-depth discussion on how the model works. I&amp;rsquo;m filing that for future research and reading once I get the opportunity to explore the textbook and associated papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#IVMOOC Week 7: Brought to you by Shinyapps and the letter R</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-03-11-ivmooc-week-7-brought-to-you-by-shinyapps-and-the-letter-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-03-11-ivmooc-week-7-brought-to-you-by-shinyapps-and-the-letter-r/</guid>
      <description>Due to the nature of this week in the course, I&amp;rsquo;ve created my visualization and reflection using R, shinyapps.io and various wonderful packages.
You can find my reflection and submission here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>52Vis - Homeless</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2016-04-12-52vis-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2016-04-12-52vis-homeless/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve a confession to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a terrible blogger. I do so out of need and interest, and I&amp;rsquo;ve a lot of the latter but little of the former.
 &amp;ldquo;The game has changed.&amp;rdquo; Clu
 (Yes, Tron Returns. Get over it.)
Bob Rudis, @hrbrmstr, a useR, visualization practitioner, data-driven security expert, blogger has constructed a wonderful set of information visualization challenges for the next year. (There goes my free time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affectively effective</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2014/10/24/affectively-effective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2014/10/24/affectively-effective/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to consider myself as a self-directed, life-long learner. Rather, I would now after undergrad, grad school with a plethora of job related learning thrown in. I didn&amp;rsquo;t start that way, I had to learn. I had to create my own meaning, develop the regulation, control my own motivation, deal with my own setbacks, reflect on my learning, reflect on my behaviour. Essentially scale the summit of bloom&amp;rsquo;s taxonomy, and make my way through liminality until I found the golden lightbulb of a transformative experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you still there?</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2014-12-29-are-you-still-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2014-12-29-are-you-still-there/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes a simple pause leads to a time-out. Juggling parenthood, my normal hatrack of jobs, plus teaching put way to many demands on my time to devote it to #dalmooc, despite it being a very interesting experience. I kept up viewing some hangouts and videos when I could, but didn&amp;rsquo;t devote any effort to the assignments and community experience. So for all of my lofty goals, I fell very short in the application/implementation of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers &amp; Analytics</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2014-11-03-barriers-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2014-11-03-barriers-analytics/</guid>
      <description>This post is addressing the first assignment/question for #DALMOOC
Analytics use at this organization is largely focused on academic analytics, using the results of assessment of student learning to inform course, program and curriculum improvements. It is less of a strategic framework put forward by the institution and more of one mandated by an accrediting body for individual programs, which leaves it up to the purview of the faculty. The collection of data has been ongoing for years, and is rolling out to a wider scale in the years to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEA Reflections</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2017-06-12-ceea2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2017-06-12-ceea2017/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I get it. I don&amp;rsquo;t post often enough. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to change that though, and overhaul things around here, for a few reasons.
 Better place to showcase my own work A place for professional reflection Interaction with the rstats and visualization communities Personal portfolio  Since I was last here my kids have grown (!), my wife and I continue on the parenting journey (whee!), I launched my consulting career (Woo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goofus and Gallant: Charts</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-10-01-goofus-and-gallant-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-10-01-goofus-and-gallant-charts/</guid>
      <description>For the past couple of years I&amp;rsquo;ve been delving into the world of information visualization. Part due to intense interest, part due to job responsibilities. I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot, taken a lot of courses, and have been working to polish my skills along the way. Having a design focused background (engineering) coupled with a broad foundation of data analysis and statistics (PhD), and my own modest skills in graphics and typography has helped quite a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don&#39;t have a clever title: #IVMOOC Week 6: Networks</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-03-03-i-dont-have-a-clever-title-ivmooc-week-6-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-03-03-i-dont-have-a-clever-title-ivmooc-week-6-networks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in Boston, in the middle of training for marking of the Critical Thinking Assessment Test. The training is good, and their process is solid. Put that on top of a decent reliable and valid instrument and you&amp;rsquo;ve got something. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to see the results and the data to draw more conclusions, but so far I like it.
Anyways. #IVMOOC. After the midterm frustration, I encountered more on the self-assessment quizzes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll take &#34;Famous Titles&#34; for $400 Alex.  #IVMOOC Week 4</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-02-12-ill-take-famous-titles-for-400-alex-ivmooc-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-02-12-ill-take-famous-titles-for-400-alex-ivmooc-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Two posts in week, and two weeks of #IVMOOC down! Topical analysis this week, and keeping in theme, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. Alongside setting up data architecture, moving research along, planning future moves, and comparing and contrasting frameworks (including engineering thinking, skills, accreditation, assessment and professional behaviour), I&amp;rsquo;m eating lunch, listening to Hidetake Takayama, writing this post and trying to figure out what to make for dinner. Pretty much the same as everyone else!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IVMOOC Reflections</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-06-08-ivmooc-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-06-08-ivmooc-reflections/</guid>
      <description>So IVMOOC has been over for quite some time now. Looking back on the experience, I consider it to be a personal success. The first half of the course was interesting, and gave a good space for practise with tools and refinement of the skill set needed for visualization. The midterm and final were shenanigan-laden and badly designed assessment, but the instructors have made great steps to address the issues and commit to improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My business is with R tonight, with maps and color. #IVMOOC Week 5</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-02-22-my-business-is-with-r-tonight-with-maps-and-color-ivmooc-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-02-22-my-business-is-with-r-tonight-with-maps-and-color-ivmooc-week-5/</guid>
      <description>So the midterm has me a bit disheartened. Not because of difficulty, but because of the miscommunication between the admin and the students. In Canvas the midterm description was set to Feb 16th 8pm EST deadline. After putting my son to bed, and while making dinner, I logged into Canvas and rushed to do the midterm. Flying through it, I ended up with a 21. Then I see the next day on twitter that it&amp;rsquo;s due on the 19th, yet this wasn&amp;rsquo;t reflected on Canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of data and questions</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2014-11-04-of-data-and-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2014-11-04-of-data-and-questions/</guid>
      <description>This post was for the 2nd week of #DALMOOC
A concept/process mash up of a map. How I think the data sources of student learning can be collected at different levels within an institution, and the giant question mark of how analytics and data visualization can best be used for data-driven program and curriculum improvement, and to enhance the quality of teaching and learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pressing pause</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2014-11-18-pressing-pause/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2014-11-18-pressing-pause/</guid>
      <description>Dear #Dalmooc,
Unfortunately, I have to press pause for some time on my learning to tackle deadlines, wrap up teaching and evaluate my students and my teaching. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to catch up before the deadlines for the early competencies.
We now return you to your regularly scheduled program, already in progress.
-jk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where in the world is Carmen Sandiego?: #IVMOOC Week 3</title>
      <link>/post/content/post/2015-02-09-where-in-the-world-is-carmen-sandiego-ivmooc-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/content/post/2015-02-09-where-in-the-world-is-carmen-sandiego-ivmooc-week-3/</guid>
      <description>Getting through this week was a bit tough, not due to content or complexity, but due to life, work and winter. Being the only well parent is a lot of work. Couple that with deadlines, grant writing and research sessions made for very little free time. I made it though!
After watching the videos and hands-on clips for the week, I felt tackling this assignment was pretty easily. I chose to visualize the amount of NSF funding for Engineering Education research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>